Updated: February 4, 2021

Contact Information Phone: +1(204) 894-0916

E-mail: asif.neloy@northsouth.edu neloyn@myumanitoba.ca

Address: 87 Delorme Bay, MB, R3V 1R3

Website: https://aaneloy.netlify.app/

Additional Resource: LinkedIn, Google Scholar, Research Gate, GitHub, Kaggle

Career Interest Seeking a position in Data Science, Data Analysis, Algorithms, Data Structure and Robotics where extensive experience will be further developed and utilized. Skilled in Machine Learning, Probabilistic Statistics, Industrial Problem-Solving, Business Data visualization and Analysis and creative thinking. Commitment to providing support and essential information about trends to companies in a variety of industries and academics.

Research Interest

My primary field of research interest is **Artificial Intelligence (AI)**. Within AI, I am interested in problems related to **Probabilistic Modeling**, **Applied Machine Learning**, **Health Data Mining**, and interdisciplinary applications of **Computer Vision** in Robotics. My research revolves around understanding the fundamental principles of statistical machine learning, designing scalable algorithms with guarantees, and rigorously analyzing their computational and information-theoretic properties. Moreover, with the help of modeling and scheme of AI, I have also a substantial overview in the field of Robotics, more precisely – **Design Analysis**, **Path Finding**, **Robot Vision**, **Object Tracking** and application of **Probabilistic Models** to the Segmentation problem.

#### Education

# University of Manitoba

January 2021 - Present

66 Chancellors Cir, Winnipeg, MB R3T 2N2, Canada

• Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (MSc CSE) - Thesis Based

#### North South University

January 2015 – December 2018

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (BS CSE)
- CGPA 3.30/4.0 (89% marks)
- Specialized Trail— Artificial Intelligence
- Thesis— Early Health Prediction System for ICU Patient using Machine Learning and Cloud Computing

# Employment History

# Grader/Marker (COMP 1600)

Dept of Computer Science, University of Manitoba 66 Chancellors Cir, Winnipeg, MB R3T 2N2, Canada.

January 2021 – Present

- Grades and marks work submitted by students from tests, exams or projects.
- Provides written feedback to the students, on the quality of material presented for grading or marking.
- Meets with the employment supervisor responsible for the course(s), for purpose of orientation and receiving guidelines for grading and marking assignments and for providing written feedback to the students.

# Graduate Research Assistant

Dept of Computer Science, University of Manitoba

January 2021 – Present

66 Chancellors Cir, Winnipeg, MB R3T 2N2, Canada.

Supervised by Assistant Professor **Max Turgeon**, Ph.D, Dept of Computer science (Cross-appointed), University of Manitoba.

- Demonstrate data science capabilities through prototypes.
- Research and develop novel algorithms and techniques to advance the state of the art in Health care systems.
- Development of code and experimental platforms, running experiments, and analyzing data using machine learning.

# **Information Analyst**

Advanced Chemical Industries (ACI Ltd.)

January 2020 – January 2021

ACI Centre 245, Tejgaon Industrial Area, Dhaka-1208, Bangladesh.

- Interpret and translate data into valuable information using different machine learning models for effective analysis purposes.
- Analyze client's requirements to provide suggestions in order to deliver products that are aligned with the ultimate business requirement.
- Oversee implementation of a new system, support users in adapting to the system by ensuring proper training and guidelines.

# Graduate Research Assistant

Dept of ECE, North South University

January 2019 – January 2021

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

- Implementing the mechanical design of coupling parts in robotic systems.
- Support the design of materials for the design of rescue robots.
- Work on a research project on the implementation of the navigation algorithm to mobile robots
- Development of code and experimental platforms, running experiments, and analyzing data using machine learning.

# Graduate Teaching Assistant

Dept of ECE, North South University

September 2020 - January 2021

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

- Facilitate a discussion section or tutorial; hold weekly office hours; grade homework, programming assignments, exams, or projects; keep records; distribute and copy reading materials; prepare answer keys or supplementary notes, and act as the course web-master.
- Assisting faculty with record keeping, such as tracking attendance and calculating grades.

#### Laboratory Officer

Dept of ECE, North South University

May 2019 – January 2021

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

- Responsible for conducting the lab classes of the enrolled students.
- Lab Coursework includes implementing algorithms and theoretical concepts with respective programming languages as deemed necessary by the course curriculum.
- Also responsible for grading and marking the students in their lab classes.

# Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Dept of ECE, North South University

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

January 2019 - May 2019

- Facilitate a discussion section or tutorial; hold weekly office hours; grade homework, programming assignments, exams, or projects; keep records; distribute and copy reading materials; prepare answer keys or supplementary notes, and act as the course web-master.
- Assisting faculty with record keeping, such as tracking attendance and calculating grades.

#### Teaching

# North South University

January 2019 - Present

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

Course	Semester
CSE231L Digital Logic design	Summer 2019
CSE332L Computer Organization and Architecture	Summer 2019
CSE482L Internet and Web Technology	Summer 2019
CSE115L Programming Language I	Summer 2019
CSE331L Microprocessor Interfacing & Embedded System	Spring 2019, Fall 2019, Spring 2020, Sum-
	mer 2020, Fall 2020
CSE311L Database Management System	Spring 2020, Summer 2020, Fall 2020

CSE311L Database Management System

Spring 2020, Summer 2020, Fall 2020

# Academic Honours and Awards

- Research Assistantship Grant from Dr. Max Turgeon, University of Manitoba.
- The Visual and Automated Disease Analytics (VADA) graduate Trainee Grant.
- Certified Mentor of Robotics and Machine learning.
- Won the 1<sup>st</sup> Runner Up prize for the Undergraduate Capstone Project, Capstone Innovation Challenge, Season 6, 2018.
- Runner up IEEE day Hackathon 2017.
- Junior Board Scholarship (Class 8) for excellent academic result.

## Technical Skills

Programming and Scripting Languages: Python, C++, C, HTML, XML, SQL, Julia, R,

Assembly, Windows Azure, Shell Scripting. Operating Systems: Windows, Linux.

Data Science Tools: Tableau, SPSS, MATLAB, Apache Spark. Anaconda Libraries: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Scipy, NLTK Platforms: IBM Cloud, IBM Watson Studio, PyCharm, GIT, Docker, Arduino.

Database Tools: Oracle, MySql, DB2, MS-Access

# Workshop or Seminar Conducted

- Workshop on Robotics (Robo101): NSU ACM Student Chapter, Conducted during Spring 2017, Fall 2017, Summer 2018.
- Workshop on Intro to Machine Learning: NSU ACM Student Chapter Fall 2018
- Hour of Code: Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Fall 2018

# **Professional** Activities

• IEEE Student Member: 94560705 • ACM Student Member: 9654439

Research Facility Founder and Principal Investigator, TF-ROS Lab

February 2019 - Present

North South University, Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh.

- Members: 6 undergraduate students of North South University.
- Funding: BDT 500000 by Desire Glance Group for the fiscal year 2018-2019.

Language Proficiency **IELTS: 6.5** (W,R-6.00, L,S-7.00)

# Reviewing Experience

#### Conference:

- 2020 International Symposium on Automation, Information and Computing (ISAIC 2020). Beijing Jiaotong University, Beijing, China, December 2nd-4th, 2020.
- 2019 The Fourth International Conference on Economic and Business Management (FEBM 2019). China October 19-21, 2019.

#### Journal:

- CAAI Transactions on Intelligence Technology (2020)
- IEEE Access (2020)

#### **Book Published**

• "Let's make Robots", Publisher - Pinnacle Media, Publishing Year - November 2017. ISBN 978-984-34-3061-8.

#### **Publications**

# Refereed Journal:

- Neloy, A. A., Alam, S., Bindu, R. A.,(2020, August). Design and Implementation of a Novel Hybrid Rental Apartment Recommender System. Advances in Data Science and Adaptive Analysis. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1142/S2424922X2041003X
- Neloy, A. A., Bindu, R. A., Alam, S., Haque, R., Khan, M. S. A., Mishu, N. M., & Siddique, S. (2020, November). Alpha\_N-V2: Shortest Path Finder Automated Delivery Robot with Real-Time Object Detection and Avoiding System. Vietnam Journal of Computer Science (VJCS), Issue-7, No 4, Nov 2020.DOI: https://doi.org/10.1142/S2196888820500219
- Neloy, A. A., Arman, A., Islam, M. S., & Motahar, T. (2018). Automated Mobile Robot with RFID Scanner and Self Obstacle Avoiding System. *International Journal of Pure and Applied Mathematics*, 118(18), 3139-3150. (pdf)

#### **Book Chapter:**

- Neloy, A. A., Bindu, R. A., Alam, S., Haque, R., Khan, M. S. A., Mishu, N. M., & Siddique, S. (2020, March). Alpha-N: Shortest Path Finder Automated Delivery Robot with Obstacle Detection and Avoiding System. In Asian Conference on Intelligent Information and Database Systems, (pp. 202-213). Springer, Cham.DOI: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-41964-6\_18
- Neloy A.A., Shafayat Oshman M., Islam M.M., Hossain M.J., & Zahir Z.B. (2019). Content-Based Health Recommender System for ICU Patient. In: Chamchong R., Wong K. (eds) *Multi-disciplinary Trends in Artificial Intelligence*. MIWAI 2019. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11909. Springer, Cham. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-33709-4\_20

### Peer-Reviewed Conference Paper:

- Bindu, R. A., Neloy, A. A., Alam, S., Moni, N. J., & Siddique, S. (2019, November). Sigma-3: Integration and Analysis of a 6 DOF Robotic Arm Configuration in a Rescue Robot. In 2019 4th International Conference on Robotics and Automation Engineering (ICRAE) (pp. 6-11). IEEE. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1109/ICRAE48301.2019.9043799
- Neloy, A. A., Alam, S., Bindu, R. A., & Moni, N. J. (2019, April). Machine Learning based Health Prediction System using IBM Cloud as PaaS. In 2019 3rd International Conference on Trends in Electronics and Informatics (ICOEI) (pp. 444-450). IEEE. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1109/ICOEI.2019.8862754

- Bindu, R. A., Alam, S., & Neloy, A. A. (2019, March). A Cost-Efficient Multipurpose Service Robot using Raspberry Pi and 6 DOF Robotic Arm. In *Proceedings* of the 2019 2nd International Conference on Service Robotics Technologies (pp. 16-22). DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3325693.3325701
- Neloy, A. A., Haque, H. S., & Ul Islam, M. M. (2019, February). Ensemble Learning Based Rental Apartment Price Prediction Model by Categorical Features Factoring. In Proceedings of the 2019 11th International Conference on Machine Learning and Computing (pp. 350-356). DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3318299.3318377

### Preprint:

- Bindu, R. A., Neloy, A. A., Alam, S., & Siddique, S. (2020). 3-Survivor: A Rough Terrain Negotiable Teleoperated Mobile Rescue Robot with Passive Control Mechanism. arXiv preprint arXiv:2003.05224.
- Neloy, A. A., Oshman, M. S., Islam, M. M., Hossain, M. J., & Zahir, Z. B. (2019). Early Health Prediction System for ICU Patient using Machine Learning and Cloud Computing. (No. 1590). EasyChair.

#### Personal

Citizenship Bangladeshi Marital Status Married

Love to Walk/Run/Playing Games, read books,

Cook for others (occasionally), Travel

#### References

Max Turgeon, Ph.D. (Current Academic Supervisor)

**Assistant Professor** 

Department of Computer Science,

University of Manitoba.

email: max.turgeon@umanitoba.ca

Md. Shazzad Hosain, Ph.D. (Previous Academic Supervisor)

Professor

Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering,

North South University.

email: shazzad.hosain@northsouth.edu Office: +880255668200, Ext: 1534